pentaho.com 2019-11-05

# Legal Terms, Privacy, Cookie Policy, Ethics and Trademarks | Hitachi Vantara

## Privacy

### HITACHI VANTARA'S GLOBAL DATA PROTECTION & PRIVACY POLICY

Collectively, the terms below are referred to as the "Policy."

Hitachi Vantara Corporation and its subsidiaries (collectively "HITACHI", "us" or "we") respects and values your privacy. Hitachi Vantara's Global Data Protection & Privacy Policy discusses our methods and approach to earning the trust you put in HITACHI.

Please read this Policy and our Terms of Use carefully because, by accessing this website and any other websites owned by HITACHI (collectively, our "Site"), you agree to comply with them. Also, by submitting personal information to HITACHI, you indicate that you consent to HITACHI's collection (including via our Site), processing and use of your personal information as described within the scope of this Policy.

Please note that if you apply for a position with HITACHI, our Employee Privacy Policy and the corresponding local privacy laws of your place or residence applicable to employees and applicants will govern the collection, processing, use and international transfer of your personal data after your initial application for employment. You may obtain a copy of that policy from your recruiter or privacy@hitachivantara.com.

Please contact privacy@hitachivantara.com with any questions about this Policy.

### HITACHI'S PRIVACY MISSION

HITACHI may, in the course of business, collect personal information, including personal data regulated by the European Union (EU) General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 ("GDPR"), which is voluntarily provided by you. The potential uses of your personal information by HITACHI are outlined in this Policy.

Our policy is not to share personal information with third parties except as provided for in this Policy, to facilitate our internal information processing activities, or to comply with applicable law. We recognize that your personal information is confidential and we take steps intended to protect your personal information while it is in our possession.

### COLLECTION AND USE OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION BY HITACHI

HITACHI may invite you to provide limited business-related personal information, including but not limited to, your name, title, company address, e-mail address, telephone and fax numbers, and whether you are a current client or business partner. If you are applying for a position with HITACHI through the Site, you may be asked to submit information related to your qualifications for the position. HITACHI disclaims any legal duty to verify the accuracy of any personal information that you provide to HITACHI.

Typically, HITACHI will ask for you to submit personal information including personal data for the following purposes:

  * website registration and to permit access to restricted areas of our Site;
  * customer, supplier, and/or business partner relationship management;
  * service and asset management;
  * to evaluate and respond to inquiries and applications for employment sent over the Site;
  * purchase management;
  * marketing of products and services;
  * occupational health and safety;
  * workplace security and protection of personnel, assets and resources;
  * to fulfil administrative and information technology functions, such as making updates to our Site;
  * monitoring or demonstrating compliance with applicable legal or regulatory requirements, or internal corporate mandates;
  * compliance with legal requirements imposed on any HITACHI entity, or to defend a legal claim.

HITACHI collects personal information for legitimate business purposes and to comply with HITACHI's legal obligations. In any instance where non-mandatory information is sought, you will be notified of this at the point of collection.

### FURTHER INFORMATION ABOUT OUR SITE

HITACHI uses your personal information provided over the Site to better understand your needs and provide you with better service. Specifically, we may use your personal information to update you on the benefits and features of HITACHI's products and services and to provide you with information and material requested by you. From time to time, we may also use your personal information to contact you for market research or to provide you with marketing information we think would be of particular interest. You may control, edit or view your preferences at Hitachi Vantara's Preference Center located at https://www.hitachivantara.com/en-us/preference-center.html.

We may also collect details of your visits to our Site for system administration and to report aggregate information, such as Site traffic data, location data, logs and other communication data, the resources that you access, information about your computer and internet connection (such as IP address, operating system, browser type). This statistical data about our users' equipment, browsing actions and patterns is not intended to identify any specific individual. By providing your personal information to HITACHI, you explicitly consent to the collection of details of your visits to our system for the purpose described above.

### SENSITIVE PERSONAL INFORMATION

HITACHI does not collect, store, or process any sensitive personal information from you for the purposes described in this Policy, including sensitive personal data as regulated by the GDPR. Depending on your location, sensitive personal information may include various types of personal information relating to: race or ethnic origin; political opinions; religious or philosophical beliefs; trade union membership; genetic data; biometric data for the purpose of uniquely identifying a natural person; data concerning health; data concerning a natural person's sex life; sexual orientation or criminal record. **We request that you do not provide sensitive personal information to us.**

### INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

Personal information, including personal information collected in the European Economic Area ("EEA") or Switzerland collected by HITACHI may be transferred, stored and processed by member companies of the worldwide Hitachi organization and the Hitachi family of companies, our business partners or third-party service providers who are established in jurisdictions without comprehensive data protection laws. Transfer of information to third parties or to locations outside of your country of residence are managed in accordance with applicable laws, which may include the GDPR.

We take reasonable steps aimed to protect your personal information. These steps include implementing the European Commission's Standard Contractual Clauses for transfers of personal information from our group companies in the EEA to our other group companies. We have implemented similar appropriate safeguards with our service providers, partners and affiliates. For more information about these safeguards, please contact privacy@hitachivantara.com.

**By providing your personal information to HITACHI, you explicitly consent to the transfer of your information outside of your country of residence.**

### LEGALLY COMPELLED DISCLOSURE

There may be circumstances under which HITACHI may be legally compelled to disclose your personal information. These circumstances may include, among others, situations where disclosure is required by law applicable to HITACHI, or necessary to comply with an order of a court or governmental agency, export control, or necessary for matters of safety and security. In such cases, HITACHI will make good faith efforts to provide only that information which is the subject of the official order or request.

### DATA RETENTION

Your personal information will be retained for as long as necessary to fulfil HITACHI's legitimate business purposes, unless a longer retention period is required by applicable law.

### COOKIES

Our Site uses cookies. " _Cookies_ " are text files containing small amounts of information placed on your computer or device when you visit a website. Cookies help us improve the functionality and performance of our Site and deliver a better and more personalized service by enabling us to:

  * Estimate our audience size and usage patterns;
  * Store information about your preferences, allowing us to customize our Site according to your individual interests;
  * Recognize you when you return to our Site; and
  * Provide us with business and marketing information.

You may also receive cookies from third parties we engage to help us provide our Site. You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the appropriate setting in your browser's software. In most cases, you may refuse cookies and still fully navigate our Site. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting, so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you direct your browser to our Site.

By accessing our Site without activating the appropriate setting in your browser (as described above), you consent to HITACHI's reasonable use of cookies as described within HITACHI's Cookies Policy.

### THIRD PARTIES

HITACHI will not sell, rent, or lease your personal information to others.

Unless we have specifically informed you, obtained your consent, or are permitted or required to do so by the laws of the jurisdiction we operate in, we will only share the personal information you provide with business partners and third-party service providers who are acting on our behalf, and then only for the uses described in this Policy. Specifically, we do not disclose your personal information to third parties for the third party's own direct marketing purposes unless you have provided your affirmative consent for such a disclosure. HITACHI will take appropriate steps to ensure that these third parties protect the confidentiality and security of your personal information.

Similarly, we ask that you do not provide us with information about third parties without their permission. You represent that, when providing us information about third parties, you have obtained previous, express and informed consent of such parties to process their personal data.

### LINKS TO THIRD PARTY WEBSITES

There are several places throughout the Site that may link to other websites that do not operate under HITACHI's privacy practices. HITACHI does not endorse or make any representations about them, or any information, software or other products or materials found there, or any results that may be obtained from using them. When you link to other websites, HITACHI's privacy practices and this Policy no longer apply and HITACHI assumes no responsibility for the information or other practices of a website that is accessible through HITACHI. We encourage you to review other website privacy policies before disclosing any personal information to them.

### YOUR CHOICES

HITACHI respects your right to make your own choices about how your personal information is handled. Should you choose to subscribe to mailing lists or any registrations, and later decide to unsubscribe you may unsubscribe on our Preference Center. You can also opt out by clicking "unsubscribe" in any marketing email communications we send you, or you may contact HITACHI at privacy@hitachivantara.com.

In addition, access to certain applications or services may involve particular uses, disclosure or transfer of the personal information being collected during registration for that application or service. If required under the laws of your country of residence, you will be notified of such intended uses, transfer or disclosure and asked to provide your consent. Failure to provide your consent where so requested may mean you will not be provided access to the applications or services for which your personal information cannot be lawfully processed.

### PRIVACY RIGHTS

HITACHI strives to ensure the accuracy of your personal information, as provided to HITACHI. We will also provide you with notifications as required by applicable law.

If you are a resident of the EEA or as permitted by the laws of your jurisdiction, you may also:

  * Request access to or a copy of your personal information.
  * Request to correct, update or rectify your personal information.
  * Request that HITACHI deletes or blocks your personal data. HITACHI is unable to delete information that we deem necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and/or enforce our agreements.
  * Object to or seek a restriction on the processing of your personal data
  * Refuse to consent or revoke your consent to processing. Revoking your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your personal information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent.
  * Raise a concern to us at privacy@hitachivantara.com or the applicable data protection authority about our collection and use of your personal information.

HITACHI will respond to your requests pursuant to applicable law and in accordance with HITACHI's Data Subject Rights Policy.

Requests should be directed to online DSAR form or privacy@hitachivantara.com.

### SECURITY

We have put in place technical and organisational procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect from you and to reduce the risk of loss, unauthorized access, misuse and alteration. Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the Internet is not completely secure. Although we work very hard to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information transmitted over our Site.

### SALE OF BUSINESS ASSETS

In the unlikely event of a sale of HITACHI, a HITACHI business unit, or a HITACHI affiliate, personal information held by HITACHI may be made available to a buyer or prospective buyers in order for them to evaluate any such purchase or to operate any parts of HITACHI's business.

### MODIFICATIONS

Subject to the legal requirements of your jurisdiction of residence for notice and consent, HITACHI reserves the right to modify or amend this Policy at any time in order to adjust to applicable laws or regulations, or changes in HITACHI's practices or procedures. Where conflicts exist between the terms and conditions of this Policy and applicable national data protection laws, the latter will take precedence. This Policy is not intended to, and does not, provide rights beyond those that are prescribed by applicable national laws. The implementation date will be displayed at the bottom of this Policy.

### HITACHI CONTENT PLATFORM ANYWHERE ANDROID APPLICATION

Hitachi Content Platform (hereinafter, "HCP") Anywhere is deployed by enterprises to mobilize, manage, and protect data. The data on the HCP Anywhere mobile application is stored and managed by the particular enterprise that deployed the HCP Anywhere sever, not HITACHI. In these cases, any data subjects who wish to exercise their rights should direct their query to our customers who act as "Data Controllers".

When installed on a device, the HCP Anywhere mobile application has access to several permissions which allows it to enforce security policies on the device based on the enterprise's HCP Anywhere settings. Mainly, the application can enforce:

  * Password requirements, such as length and alphanumeric requirements
  * Maximum inactivity time
  * Storage area encryption

The HCP Anywhere mobile application enforces these policies using Device Administration. Although the HCP Anywhere mobile application can enforce certain policies on the device, it does not collect or process any personal information (e.g. Your device password).

### PRIVACY OF CHILDREN

Our Site, our products, and services are not directed to individuals under the age of thirteen. Please let us know if a person under the age of thirteen has provided HITACHI with personal information by contacting privacy@hitachivantara.com. In the event that we become aware that a child has provided us with personal information, we will implement the necessary technical and organizational measure to erase said information.

### CONTACT US

We welcome your inquiries or comments about this Policy and any queries or concerns that you may have about the Site.

Please contact HITACHI at privacy@hitachivantara.com or at the following address:

Hitachi Vantara Corporation  
2535 Augustine Drive  
Santa Clara, CA 95054 USA

Attention: Global Data Protection Officer

### IMPLEMENTATION DATE

We review HITACHI'S Privacy Policy regularly to reflect changes introduced by the applicable legislation. If you continue using our Site after such revisions are in effect, you accept and agree to the revisions and to abide by them.

This Policy was last updated on May 21, 2019.
